Edmilson Dos Santos Jr

Web Developer

358 Fountain St. Apt. 3 Fall River, MA - 02721 edossantosjr@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Web Developer with more than 2+ years experience in structuring, developing and implementing mid to large-scale websites and web-applications based on web standard technologies such as HTML5, CSS, JavaScript. I am able to complete projects efficiently and satisfy customers with modern user-friendly websites. I am passionate about writing great code.

Technical Skills

- XHTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3
- Responsive Web Design
- CSS preprocessors, LESS, SASS
- Twitter Bootstrap
- JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone.js
- CMS, WordPress, PHP

- Ecommerce, OpenCart
- Ruby, Sinatra
- APIs, Grape, Swagger UI
- Grunt, Gulp, Brunch
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, Rethink dB
- Npm, Bower, Git, Mercurial

Employment Experience

STATEWIDE SOFTWARE & SYSTEMS, NEW BEDFORD, MA Full Stack Web Developer

Apr. 2014 to Current

- Work closely with a Senior Developer to manage large, complex projects.
- Design and implement backend services and APIs in Ruby to support mobile applications.
- Develop customized Admin dashboards to track and manager order fulfillment.
- Develop ecommerce websites for businesses.
- Create custom WordPress themes and adapt plugins to satisfy clients' needs.

- Develop fast cross-browser web pages.
- Produce Wireframes and Mockups to visualize the different user flow.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: HTML, CSS3 (less/sass), Bootstrap, Responsive Design, jQuery, ECMAScript6, Backbone, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Rethink DB, Grunt, Bower, Brunch, Git, WordPress, OpenCart(e-commerce), Facebook API.

SNOOWL INC., FALL RIVER, MA Full Stack Web Developer - Contractor

Jun. 2015 to Dec. 2015

- Designed & Developed a Premium marketing tool used to promote small local businesses.
- Designed and implemented backend services and APIs to support iOS Application.
- Developed Embedded Web View for iOS Application using HTML, CSS, Knockout.js to quick roll out features.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: HTML, CSS3 (Less/Sass), Bootstrap, Responsive Design, jQuery, Knockout.js, JRuby, Rethink DB, Grunt, Facebook API, Stripe API.

822 FALL RIVER AVE LEASING CORP, SEEKONK, MA Sep.2007 to Apr.2013 Assistant Manager

- Delivered excellent customer service.
- Directed and supervised employees engaged in sales and inventory-taking.

Education

Bristol Community College, Fall River, MA

Candidate for Associates in Science in Computer Information systems, Concentration: Webmaster

August 2016

Awards

CIS – Web Developer Programmer Award Bristol Community College, Fall River, MA June 2014